<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pawelgrzybek.com</title>
    <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/</link>
    <description>Hi there, I&#39;m Pawel Grzybek, Front-end Developer from Poland. Nowadays I live in Leicester (UK). When I&#39;m not coding, I&#39;m spinning funky vinyl records.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pawelgrzybek.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple SSH keys for multiple Bitbucket/GitHub accounts</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/multiple-ssh-keys-for-multiple-bitbucket-github-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/multiple-ssh-keys-for-multiple-bitbucket-github-accounts/</guid>
      <description>If we cannot use singular SSH key across multiple accounts (what makes a perfect sense) the solution is to have multiple of them. Let&#39;s create two new pair of SSH keys, one for personal use and another one for the clients project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: The Fast 800: How to Combine Rapid Weight Loss and Intermittent Fasting for Long-Term Health by Dr Michael Mosley</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-the-fast-800-how-to-combine-rapid-weight-loss-and-intermittent-fasting-for-long-term-health-by-dr-michael-mosley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-the-fast-800-how-to-combine-rapid-weight-loss-and-intermittent-fasting-for-long-term-health-by-dr-michael-mosley/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve tried out multiple diets which have given me various results, but intermittent fasting is something that I&#39;ve heard around a lot but never actually tried. I was browsing the Audible library recently and have been eager to spend my credit points on something informative. I came across &#34;The Fast 800: How to Combine Rapid Weight Loss and Intermittent Fasting for Long-Term Health&#34; by Dr Michael Mosley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute a shell command inside a Docker container (3 methods)</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/execute-a-shell-command-inside-a-docker-container-3-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/execute-a-shell-command-inside-a-docker-container-3-methods/</guid>
      <description>Running projects inside containers is a bread and butter task of a developers life. It’s not rare to need to execute a command against a container and Docker gives us multiple options to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-july/</guid>
      <description>Chrome web.dev Live 2020, new approach to work with dates in JavaScript, Svelte with a support for TypeScript, AWS SAM frameworks hits stable version 1.0.0 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IP address, subnet mask and CIDR notation</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-ip-address-subnet-mask-and-cidr-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-ip-address-subnet-mask-and-cidr-notation/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is a big network of devices, each of them is identified by the unique IP address. Subnetting is a process of dividing them into smaller subnetworks. Subnet mask helps us to determine which part of the IP address belongs to the network and which one belongs to us (host).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Node.js Streams</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/understanding-nodejs-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/understanding-nodejs-streams/</guid>
      <description>Streams in nature flow water from one side to the other, streams in programming are the same but instead of water, they flow chunks of data. It is a sequential way of handling chunks of bytes. You can achieve a lot without using streams at all, but a thorough understanding of them will make you a much better developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was invited to the Mindera Yellow Box Podcast to chat the state of the Web development</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-was-invited-to-the-mindera-yellow-box-podcast-to-chat-the-state-of-the-web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-was-invited-to-the-mindera-yellow-box-podcast-to-chat-the-state-of-the-web-development/</guid>
      <description>It was my podcasting debut and I was a bit stressed, but I managed to convey the message and I&#39;m quite proud of how it&#39;s turned out! You might disagree with some opinions, which is fine, I&#39;m more than happy to have a beer and discuss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-june/</guid>
      <description>Accessibility features in The Last of Us Part II, consideration of picking a right monitor for development, bunch of great news in Safari 14, HTML Essential Training and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Not a Diet Book by James Smith</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-not-a-diet-book-by-james-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-not-a-diet-book-by-james-smith/</guid>
      <description>My 30th birthday was the last time I felt great in my own body. My 33rd birthday is coming soon and I promised myself that I’m going to feel great with myself again. Whilst I change my diet habits and become much more active, I try to educate myself on how to do it healthily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Brzydki, Zły i Szczery by Adam Ostrowski</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-brzydki-zly-i-szczery-by-adam-ostrowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-brzydki-zly-i-szczery-by-adam-ostrowski/</guid>
      <description>MC and producer Adam Ostrowski, better known as O.S.T.R. reveals quite a lot of his art but also personal life. His autobiography is funny and easy to read but also emotional and filled with passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Steve Jobs: The Exclusive Biography by Walter Isaacson</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-steve-jobs-the-exclusive-biography-by-walter-isaacson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-steve-jobs-the-exclusive-biography-by-walter-isaacson/</guid>
      <description>It is a very compelling read about the genius and the biggest asshat under the moon. From his childhood and throughout education, including projects and the loosing the battle with cancer. I would highly recommend this book not only to Apple fans, but to everyone who needs an inspirational kick in their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-may/</guid>
      <description>Insomnia Designer to help us edit and share OpenAPI specifications, new GitHub features announced on GitHub Satellite, Logical assignment in JavaScript, new CSS layout features, Deno hits version 1.0, MongoDB for Visual Studio Code and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native lazy-loading of images on Hugo based website</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-lazy-loading-of-images-on-hugo-based-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-lazy-loading-of-images-on-hugo-based-website/</guid>
      <description>The implementation of lazy-loading images using Hugo is equally simple as adding it to an HTML file and you don’t have a good reason not to do so. Let me explain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite Visual Studio Code tips for &#34;how did you do it&#34; kind of people</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-visual-studio-code-tips-for-how-did-you-do-it-kind-of-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-visual-studio-code-tips-for-how-did-you-do-it-kind-of-people/</guid>
      <description>Would you like to learn a few little tips for  productivity, keyboard shortcuts and little known Visual Studio Code hidden gems. This article is for you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Permanent Record by Edward Snowden</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-permanent-record-by-edward-snowden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-permanent-record-by-edward-snowden/</guid>
      <description>My friend Kyran recently recommended &#34;Permanent Record&#34; a book about a story that I had heard before from the movie &#34;Snowden&#34;. It&#39;s been a while since I watched it, so I decided to be a bit more curious about the controversial story of NSA&#39;s employee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-april/</guid>
      <description>DNS server for families from CloudFlare, interesting CSS elements in new Facebook design, consideration for mocking objects in your unit tests, free GitHub for teams, TypeScript’s type notation, full-height element on iOS Safari and more… </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mocking functions and modules with Jest</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/mocking-functions-and-modules-with-jest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/mocking-functions-and-modules-with-jest/</guid>
      <description>To write deterministic, repeatable unit tests, we need to control the inputs, outputs and invocations of mock objects. The Jest testing framework comes with great mocking capabilities. Let&#39;s have a look at them all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: The Lean Startup by Eric Ries</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-the-lean-startup-by-eric-ries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-the-lean-startup-by-eric-ries/</guid>
      <description>&#34;Business&#34; is not the number one category of books that I would usually go for but despite this, I think that it&#39;s good to diverge and embrace a project development from a different perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in ECMAScript 2020</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2020/</guid>
      <description>The list of new ECMAScript 2020 features is set in stone. Let’s have a look at what’s coming this year and a few practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-march/</guid>
      <description>GOV.UK Design System team changed the input type for numbers, MonoLisa — stunning font family designed for software developers, npm is joining GitHub, CSS :nth-of-class selector, imact of CSS on screenreaders and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS feed for youtube channels and GitHub project</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/rss-feed-for-youtube-channels-and-github-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/rss-feed-for-youtube-channels-and-github-project/</guid>
      <description>Today a quick tip but a massive time saver in the long run. Let&#39;s stop being hooked on suggested youtube vides and watch only what we really care about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Endurance by Scott Kelly</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-endurance-by-scott-kelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-endurance-by-scott-kelly/</guid>
      <description>I have always been curious about the subject of space travel, living in such a distant place and the daily life and routines out there. I couldn&#39;t have picked a better book to satisfy my curiosity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-february/</guid>
      <description>The Web We Want initiative, HTTPS Is Easy, new JavaScript bundler coded entirely in a go language, revolutionary TypeScript 3.8 changes, Firefox and Edge Support in Cypress 4.0 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Humble Pi: A Comedy of Maths Errors by Matt Parker</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-humble-pi-a-comedy-of-maths-errors-by-matt-parker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-humble-pi-a-comedy-of-maths-errors-by-matt-parker/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that I have never had a trophy for being the best maths student at school, I always enjoyed mathematics. I can get through some simple equations but everything more challenging than trigonometry or matrices normally ends up being a spectacular fiasco. My failures are very insignificant compared to the ones described in the book that I just read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Gravitas by Caroline Goyder</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-gravitas-by-caroline-goyder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-gravitas-by-caroline-goyder/</guid>
      <description>I am a constant joker! Most of the time there&#39;s nothing bad about this, but in a senior-level position in big software company, some level of seriousness can be helpful. The power to be a great communicator lies somewhere in-between, doesn&#39;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2020 January</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2020-january/</guid>
      <description>TSConf 2019 talks are online! Dan Abramov ans his advice abour writing a clean code, animate text along the SVG path, Microsoft Edge on Chromium, beautiful JetBrains Mono, Yarn 2 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL — git switch &amp; git restore</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/til-git-switch-git-restore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/til-git-switch-git-restore/</guid>
      <description>Switching branches and restoring files to its initial state are very common operations. Why the hell should we use a single command to perform such different actions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Peter Pan</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-peter-pan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-peter-pan/</guid>
      <description>After the last decade that I’ve spent reading serious, mature, programming and science-related books, I decided to re-experience that feeling of pure adventure and make-believe which comes from reading a children’s book. I don&#39;t regret this decision and I am sure I am going to read more toddler novels soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Atomic Habits: An Easy &amp; Proven Way to Build Good Habits &amp; Break Bad Ones by James Clear</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-atomic-habits-an-easy-proven-way-to-build-good-habits-break-bad-ones-by-james-clear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/book-review-atomic-habits-an-easy-proven-way-to-build-good-habits-break-bad-ones-by-james-clear/</guid>
      <description>I have always been reading a ton but this year I am planning to make a subject shift. Less nerdy technical gibberish and more stuff that can help me to be a better version of myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 December</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-december/</guid>
      <description>Screen readers explained, graphQL connections demystified, Quoting in HTML, the State of JavaScript in 2019, Const Assertions in TypeScript, hot tips to become a better Node.js developer, the CSS Containment Specification and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at 2019</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2019/</guid>
      <description>Allow me to use this post-Christmas time as an excuse to share some achievements and failures from the past year. It is also a great opportunity to think about some goals for the coming year, 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attach Visual Studio Code debugger to SAM (Serverless Application Model) local endpoint</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/attach-visual-studio-code-debugger-to-sam-serverless-application-model-local-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/attach-visual-studio-code-debugger-to-sam-serverless-application-model-local-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>A debugger is something that I cannot live without. Setting it up for my current project built using SAM framework and TypeScript took me a while but I finally got it right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 November</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-november/</guid>
      <description>Variable Fonts, Visual Studio Online, Implicit State Machines, TypeScript 3.7, Chrome Dev Summit 2019, new methods on String prototype, Google Metrics, CSS Logical Properties, AWS FIFO SQS and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does JavaScript keep you too busy to care about CSS? Here are recent features you want to know about!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/does-javascript-keep-you-too-busy-to-care-about-css-here-are-recent-features-you-want-to-know-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/does-javascript-keep-you-too-busy-to-care-about-css-here-are-recent-features-you-want-to-know-about/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I have been busy exploring the world of JavaScript to the point that I neglected my passion for CSS. I owe CSS a debt so I curated a list of recent features that you may want to know about if you didn&#39;t follow this space for a little while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 October</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-october/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Sass Modules, 100% CSS Mario Kart, Faces of Open Source, React Concurrent Modem, the two-value syntax of the CSS Display property and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to React Advanced London</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-react-advanced-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-react-advanced-london/</guid>
      <description>Whenever it comes to frontend apps, React is the tool that I feel the most comfortable with. Couldn&#39;t be happier when organizers reached out to me and invited me to React Advanced London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL — The power of JSON.stringify replacer parameter</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/til-the-power-of-json-stringify-replacer-parameter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/til-the-power-of-json-stringify-replacer-parameter/</guid>
      <description>I had a challenging problem with JSON stringify that ignored my data in a place where I expected sets of values. Luckily I managed to solve it in a very elegant way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 September</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-september/</guid>
      <description>Writing for big publications, Command Line Heroes podcast, TypeScript vs ReasonML, Can I use merges with MDN, FaunaDB on Netlify, great guide to HTML5 `&lt;head&gt;` elements and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to MongoDB.local London 2019</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-mongodb-local-london-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-mongodb-local-london-2019/</guid>
      <description>Being a MongoDB user I could not wait to go to MongoDB.local London 2019. Having an opportunity to learn the subject from its creators is irreplaceable and this time it wasn&#39;t an exception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 August</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-august/</guid>
      <description>Google’s “core updates”, get experience as a software engineer, WebKit Tracking Prevention Policy, optional chaining in JavaScript and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promise combinators explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/promise-combinators-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/promise-combinators-explained/</guid>
      <description>Promise.all, Promise.race, Promise.allSettled and Promise.any help us a lot with operations on compound promises. Let me clarify the difference between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-july/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript global variables, Netlify Analytics, AWS Toolkit for Visual Studio Code, Algebraic Effects, CSS Lists, Markers, Counters and Margins, optional chaining and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing! Instagram line break!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-instagram-line-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-instagram-line-break/</guid>
      <description>Instagram doesn&#39;t want you to insert line breaks in captions and bios. Thats the reason why I created this little web app. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a local WordPress development using Docker</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/configure-a-local-wordpress-development-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/configure-a-local-wordpress-development-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>WordPress being the absolute top of the podium of user-friendly content management systems can be cumbersome to spin up locally. Docker containers are perfect for tasks like this so let me explain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-june/</guid>
      <description>The Evolution Of A Brand, plugins are coming to Figma, WWDC19 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple changed the default shell from bash to zsh, so did I</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/apple-changed-the-default-shell-from-bash-to-zsh-so-did-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/apple-changed-the-default-shell-from-bash-to-zsh-so-did-i/</guid>
      <description>Love it or hate it but since macOS Catalina the default shell language is zsh. I am very excited about this decision so let me share with you my favourite parts of the new command-line interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-may/</guid>
      <description>Flutter framework is exploding on Google I/O, Windows Subsystem for Linux 2, Windows Terminal, CodeSandbox raises $2.4M, font-display on Google Fonts, HTML Portals, GitHub Package Registry, Node 10 on AWS Lambda, collaboration between W3C and WHATWG and much more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TypeScript interface vs. type</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/typescript-interface-vs-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/typescript-interface-vs-type/</guid>
      <description>Should it be an interface or a type alias? This is a question asked a lot by newcomers. Let me clarify the difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-april/</guid>
      <description>Google Chrome Network tab explained, CSS scroll-margin and scroll-padding,native lazy-loading for images and iframes is coming, Front-end Developer Handbook 2019, performance hints guide, state management in React apps in 2019, native ECMAScript modules in Node.js and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing — httpsc (Simple HTTP status codes reference CLI)</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-httpsc-simple-http-status-codes-reference-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-httpsc-simple-http-status-codes-reference-cli/</guid>
      <description>How often do you visit a Wikipedia for a definition of a HTTP status code? I don&#39;t know how about you but it happens to me at least once a week. To make it a bit easier I created a httpsc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-march/</guid>
      <description>CSS Math Functions are coming, KV Storage, promissing plans for Sketch App, Aspect Ratio unit in CSS, Stadia, Amazon Glacier even more cost effective and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build your first AWS Serverless app</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/build-your-first-aws-serverless-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/build-your-first-aws-serverless-app/</guid>
      <description>After years spent working on frontend development, through building AR / VR applications, I recently ended up in a team of talented people building serverless microservices on the AWS platform. Let me share with you some of my experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-february/</guid>
      <description>React Hooks landed in v16.8, CSS position sticky explained, State of JavaScript Frameworks &amp; Libraries, future of TSLint and Twelve-Factor App Methodology to Serverless Applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in ECMAScript 2019</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2019/</guid>
      <description>The final list of features that are joining the ECMAScript specification this year is ready. Here&#39;s a quick summary and look at some practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2019 January</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2019-january/</guid>
      <description>Algorithmic layouts by Heydon Pickering, free private repos on GitHub, the future of TypeScript linting and AWS services explained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linting TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/linting-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/linting-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Lint or not to lint? TSLint or ESLint? It is hard to decide what to use to identify potential errors. Let me elaborate why I chose ESLint to help me doing that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Node.js — installer vs. Homebrew vs. NVM</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/install-nodejs-installer-vs-homebrew-vs-nvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/install-nodejs-installer-vs-homebrew-vs-nvm/</guid>
      <description>There is plenty of ways to install Node.js and I am about to show you the most popular methods and highlight pros and cons of each of them</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 December</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-december/</guid>
      <description>Chromium-based Anaheim browser on Windows, Dan Abramov started his blog, WordPress 5 Bebo landed and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at 2018</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2018/</guid>
      <description>Another New Year&#39;s Eve is on the horizon — the perfect time to summarise the things that went well, not so well and make some plans for the next twelve months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 November</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-november/</guid>
      <description>How V8 handles promises and async / await functions, Chrome Dev Summit 2018, The State of JavaScript, Custom Elements for React developers and the future of programming by uncle Bob.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-cutting functionality in React using Higher-Order Components, Render Props and Hooks</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cross-cutting-functionality-in-react-using-higher-order-components-render-props-and-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cross-cutting-functionality-in-react-using-higher-order-components-render-props-and-hooks/</guid>
      <description>When working with modern JavaScript frameworks we often have to share the same piece of functionality across multiple components. Let me explain a few patterns that make this a breeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 October</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-october/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Solid, Create React App 2.0, the state of Houdini API, Adobe Fonts, GitHub Actions, relative time format is coming to JavaScript, React 16.6 released and Hooks announced on React Conf 2018. Very crazy month!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing! PinBuddy!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-pinbuddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-pinbuddy/</guid>
      <description>PinBuddy is a Google Chrome toolbar extension for the Pinboard bookmarking service that lets you browse and add new bookmarks with ease. It is fully keyboard accessible and highlights previously bookmarked websites. It uses API tokens for server communications and never asks for your authentication credentials hence secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 September</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-september/</guid>
      <description>React Fire and changes to React DOM, CSS Scroll Snapping, GitHub PRs in Visual Studio Code, animations in UX and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did you learn today?</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/what-did-you-learn-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/what-did-you-learn-today/</guid>
      <description>Since I joined Mindera a few months ago I&#39;ve cultivated a daily habit — at some point in the day I&#39;ll ask my team members…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 August</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-august/</guid>
      <description>Why your skip links are broken, CSS Grid visualized, native lazy load, the state of mobile platforms, whats new in Babel 7, color formats and InDesign killer. This and much more on this month top picks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Versioning (SemVer) explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/semantic-versioning-semver-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/semantic-versioning-semver-explained/</guid>
      <description>The versioning of software seems to be a confusing concept for developers. The meaning behind the versioning format isn&#39;t coming out of the blue so let me help you to understand it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capture One Pro — the best parts</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/capture-one-pro-the-best-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/capture-one-pro-the-best-parts/</guid>
      <description>Amongst the multiple RAW image converters available on the market, I settled with the one by Phase One. Let me share with you a few reasons why I made this choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-july/</guid>
      <description>Npm joins TC39! Affinity Designer for iPad! Moment for iOS! Accessibility for Teams! CSS Container Queries! State of Browsers! CSS Shapes! TypeScript 3.0 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebrew — the best friend of the macOS user</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/homebrew-the-best-friend-of-the-macos-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/homebrew-the-best-friend-of-the-macos-user/</guid>
      <description>As a curious human being you are probably doing a lot of monotonous tasks: installing and removing software, switching versions of dependencies and searching for new tools. Make your life easier with Homebrew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-june/</guid>
      <description>Guide to open source, GitHub joins Microsoft, WWDC 2018, CORS, accessible cards, CSS Blocks, DNS over HTTPS, Vue passed React, ECMAScript 2018 and more…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; for JavaScript developers</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cpp-for-javascript-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cpp-for-javascript-developers/</guid>
      <description>One of my resolutions for 2018 is to learn a new programming language. I decided to go with C++ and after a few months, I am ready to share with you some of my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-may/</guid>
      <description>Arbitrary-precision integers in JavaScript, GitHub Pages gain support for HTTPS, LinkedIn’s new open source projects take on stylesheet performance, Multi-User access on Cloudflare, the best of Google I/O ’18, Prisma revolution, hard parts of JavaScript explained in simple words and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks for everything Engine Creative! Hi Mindera!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-for-everything-engine-creative-hi-mindera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-for-everything-engine-creative-hi-mindera/</guid>
      <description>Time moves on, my perception about life has taken shape and my list of priorities have changed order. I am super happy to announce that I am leaving the Engine Creative family to join Mindera!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-april/</guid>
      <description>New DNS server by Cloudflare and APNIC, responsive images explained, machine learning in JavaScript, CSS floats demystified, big node / npm update, new version of git Tower is coming and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure a local WordPress development on macOS from scratch</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/configure-a-local-wordpress-development-on-macos-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/configure-a-local-wordpress-development-on-macos-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>So you&#39;re about to build a WordPress website. An Apache HTTP Server, PHP and MySQL database is all that you need. Let me guide you step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Jekyll to Hugo! From GitHub Pages to Netlify!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-jekyll-to-hugo-from-github-pages-to-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-jekyll-to-hugo-from-github-pages-to-netlify/</guid>
      <description>After a few years of blogging using Jekyll, my website became slow and I stopped enjoying working on fresh content. Hugo and Netlify have solved my problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-march/</guid>
      <description>Prototyping and cloud libraries in Sketch 49, tons of cool stuff on React&#39;s world, C++ must have, shocking results of Stackoverflow Developer Survey and CSS Typed Object Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siema! Thanks for 2000 stars on Github!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/siema-thanks-for-2000-stars-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/siema-thanks-for-2000-stars-on-github/</guid>
      <description>In November 2016 I was looking for a carousel for one of my projects. I couldn&#39;t find one that fulfills my requirements so I built one. Months have passed, hours have been spent on the project and 280 commits later…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-february/</guid>
      <description>Math concepts explained better, Phase — another Sketch compeitor is coming, event loop in JavaScript, debugging Node.js in VSCode and danger that comes with using third party scripts and stylesheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Amazon S3 photo backup solution</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-amazon-s3-photo-backup-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-amazon-s3-photo-backup-solution/</guid>
      <description>As an amateur photographer I have been looking for a cloud backup solution for years. Keeping a physical backup on an external hard drive is definitely not enough. Then I came across Amazon S3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing - an Alfred workflow to manage Things lists</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-an-alfred-workflow-to-manage-things-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-an-alfred-workflow-to-manage-things-lists/</guid>
      <description>Alfred is my favourite productivity booster for macOS. Things is my GTD tool of choice that perfectly suits my workflow. I&#39;ve connected the power of the two apps together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2018 January</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2018-january/</guid>
      <description>Easier purchase process with the Payment Request API, improvements to the Web Animations API, Array &amp; Object explorer, changes in Apple Developer Program, HDR Photography in Microsoft Excel, rise of the state machines, HTML 5.2, AMP drama, JavaScript frameworks, CSS Print API, brand new Bootstrap 4, CSS Grid by Wes Bos, laws of good UX, mobile search ranking changes, HTTPS everywhere, Safari meets Service Workers and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Resize Observer explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-resize-observer-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-resize-observer-explained/</guid>
      <description>How many occasions have you attached a resize listener to a whole document just to track changes on a single DOM element? Those times are over — the Resize Observer is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in ECMAScript 2018</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2018/</guid>
      <description>The last TC39 meeting resulted in finalised features set for ECMAScript 2018. This article presents all the new goodies — let&#39;s get on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 December</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-december/</guid>
      <description>React explained one more time, non-config bundler called Parcel, Turbo as a new npm alternative, mobile first indexing enable by default, better adds, JavaScript compiled to binaries and more on the last top picks of a 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at 2017</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2017/</guid>
      <description>Another New Year&#39;s Eve is coming — the perfect time to summarise the things that went well, list the fails and make some plans for the next twelve months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change macOS user preferences via command line</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/change-macos-user-preferences-via-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/change-macos-user-preferences-via-command-line/</guid>
      <description>The system preferences window is not the only way to change user preferences in macOS. The &#34;defaults&#34; command gives you more power to configure your machine than you would have thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 November</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-november/</guid>
      <description>Fragment shaders, real time session sharing in Visual Studio Code, tons of smooth CSS animations, dynamic import in JavaScript, current state of publishing, CSS element function and brand new overscroll-behavior, garbage collector of JS engines and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity development on macOS with Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/unity-development-on-macos-with-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/unity-development-on-macos-with-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <description>As a fresh Unity developer I really struggled to jump from my favourite code editor to MonoDevelop. It took me a while to realize that this actually isn&#39;t a necessity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 October</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-october/</guid>
      <description>EDGE on Android and iOS, sliders in pure CSS and HTML, all about CDNs, Quantum by Firefox, InVision Studio, XD out of beta, MDN become the only source of truth and more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From callback hell, through promises to async functions</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-a-callback-hell-through-promises-to-async-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-a-callback-hell-through-promises-to-async-functions/</guid>
      <description>The last few years have brought us lots of revolutionary features for working with asynchronous JavaScript operations. Let&#39;s review the most popular ones together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return multiple elements from a component with React 16</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/return-multiple-elements-from-a-component-with-react-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/return-multiple-elements-from-a-component-with-react-16/</guid>
      <description>One of the most requested features in React framework has always been returning multiple elements from a components render method. There you have it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 September</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-september/</guid>
      <description>This month was crazy! Brand new React, big licensing changes, Sketch Libraries, new Sublime Text release, CSS constants, EDGE 16, Promise API updates and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks to BrowserStack</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-browserstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/thanks-to-browserstack/</guid>
      <description>Testing across multiple platforms, devices and browsers is hard and having a tool that makes this process seamless is irreplaceable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 August</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-august/</guid>
      <description>Do you like Comic Sans? How about webfonts fallbacks? Image compression? A bit about Unity updates and some async JS tips. Check this month top picks out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Observer Pattern in JavaScript explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-observer-pattern-in-javascript-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-observer-pattern-in-javascript-explained/</guid>
      <description>This popular pattern used by tons of JavaScript applications may save you from injecting costly dependencies in your project. Easy, clean and very useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-july/</guid>
      <description>Node.js authentication, the hardest accessibility issue about browsing the web, GraphQL tutorial, the future of Adobe Flash, brand new Figma with build it prototyping mode and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing - Bimbo Theme for Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-bimbo-theme-for-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-bimbo-theme-for-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <description>After switching from Sublime Text to VS Code I was looking for a theme that didn&#39;t exist — so I built one. Totally for free! From a developer for developers. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-june/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using webpack with gulp.js</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/using-webpack-with-gulpjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/using-webpack-with-gulpjs/</guid>
      <description>Webpack is a module bundler for modern JavaScript apps. Gulp describes itself as a platform-agnostic task runner. Can they work together? Easily! Take a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning DOM nodes and handling attached events</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cloning-dom-nodes-and-handling-attached-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/cloning-dom-nodes-and-handling-attached-events/</guid>
      <description>As a creator and maintainer of a popular DOM library, I found myself in a situation where I had to clone an element. Sounds trivial? This is what I learnt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Node.js debugging in Google Chrome</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/basic-nodejs-debugging-in-google-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/basic-nodejs-debugging-in-google-chrome/</guid>
      <description>We have been testing front-end code in Google Chrome Dev Tools for quite a while. How about testing Node.js code in exactly the same way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-may/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing - Snippet Generator for VS Code, Sublime Text and Atom</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-snippet-generator-for-vs-code-sublime-text-and-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-snippet-generator-for-vs-code-sublime-text-and-atom/</guid>
      <description>Snippets — probably the most powerful feature of code editors. I love using them but I don&#39;t like creating them manually. Let me simplify things a little bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-april/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make some magic with CSS blend modes</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/make-some-magic-with-css-blend-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/make-some-magic-with-css-blend-modes/</guid>
      <description>Remember the bloody wars between web designers and front-end developers about blend modes? Those times are over — thanks to the power of CSS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native ECMAScript modules in the browser</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-ecmascript-modules-in-the-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-ecmascript-modules-in-the-browser/</guid>
      <description>Javascript modules have been a part of the spec for a little while now but it&#39;s taken some time to see the first implementation in a web browser. Finally, we have it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-march/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluent interfaces explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/fluent-interfaces-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/fluent-interfaces-explained/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a program that is written like a sentence instead of a series of separated command blocks — the technique of method chaining is the answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-february/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My setup — 2017 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-setup-2017-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-setup-2017-february/</guid>
      <description>Which hardware, software and web apps other professionals are using is something that I enjoy reading about. Today&#39;s post is about my own setup from February 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2017 January</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2017-january/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in ECMAScript 2017</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2017/</guid>
      <description>Introduced in 2015, the ECMAScript annual release plan aims to add to the language any proposals that are ready at the time of the TC39 meeting. Here&#39;s what&#39;s new in ES2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the JavaScript console in Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/using-the-javascript-console-in-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/using-the-javascript-console-in-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <description>The JavaScript console in the browser is one of the most popular debugging methods. It would be cool to see its output straight in the code editor, wouldn&#39;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync VSCode settings and snippets via dotfiles on Github</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/sync-vscode-settings-and-snippets-via-dotfiles-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/sync-vscode-settings-and-snippets-via-dotfiles-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Having access to the same settings and snippets across multiple devices is a handy feature of some text editors. This is how to do it in VSCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A look back at 2016</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/a-look-back-at-2016/</guid>
      <description>The new year is a great opportunity for an annual summary and a great time to set new goals for the upcoming year. Time to reveal a bit of the professional and personal sides of myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 December</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-december/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I built a thing! Siema!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-siema/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-built-a-thing-siema/</guid>
      <description>Siema - a very lightweight (just 1kb gzipped) carousel plugin with no dependencies. It&#39;s well supported and ready to use on personal and commercial projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the deal with the Pointer Events in JavaScript?</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-the-deal-with-the-pointer-events-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-the-deal-with-the-pointer-events-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>How do you handle mouse events but maintain a good experience for users using their finger as the input device? How about pens / styluses? Pointer events to the rescue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 November</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-november/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 October</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-october/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loop through a collection of DOM elements</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/loop-through-a-collection-of-dom-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/loop-through-a-collection-of-dom-elements/</guid>
      <description>Looping through a NodeList isn&#39;t as easy as iterating over a JavaScript array. In this article I am going to cover the possible methods (and hacks) to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 September</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-september/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trailing comma in ECMAScript 2017 function parameter list</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/trailing-comma-in-ecmascript2017-function-parameter-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/trailing-comma-in-ecmascript2017-function-parameter-list/</guid>
      <description>Object and array literals already allow us to leave a trailing comma. ECMAScript 2017 adds the same functionality to the function parameter list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync Atom between multiple devices</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/sync-atom-between-multiple-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/sync-atom-between-multiple-devices/</guid>
      <description>Syncing the preferences and extensions of my code editor between all of my devices is part of my productive workflow. Here are a few methods to do it with Atom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 August</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-august/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Div — a simple Alfred window manager</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/div-simple-alfred-windows-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/div-simple-alfred-windows-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to present you Div — a simple Alfred window manager. Let me explain the full potential of this easy and powerful tool in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-july/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page scrolling in vanilla JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/page-scroll-in-vanilla-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/page-scroll-in-vanilla-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Scrolling to an element on a page has always been easy with jQuery. It&#39;s a bit tricky in vanilla JavaScript — but definitely doable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-june/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intersection Observer API explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-intersection-observer-api-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-intersection-observer-api-explained/</guid>
      <description>Detecting when elements become visible on the viewport has always been an expensive task. Not anymore — the Intersection Observer API just landed in Chromium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-may/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to the Web Animations API</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/intro-to-the-web-animations-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/intro-to-the-web-animations-api/</guid>
      <description>We have many methods available to move things around on the web. Let’s embrace the power of future animations with the Web Animations API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest style layout with Bricky</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/pinterest-style-layout-with-bricky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/pinterest-style-layout-with-bricky/</guid>
      <description>The Pinterest / Masonry style layout has always been tricky to create so I&#39;ve created a very lightweight and dependency-free plugin called Bricky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-april/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS mixins with @apply rule</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-mixins-with-apply-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-mixins-with-apply-rule/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m excited about a recently added CSS features. Previously we discussed custom properties, now it&#39;s a time to talk about mixins using the @apply rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquid video</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/liquid-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/liquid-video/</guid>
      <description>Make your iframe videos from YouTube or Vimeo responsive with ease with simple script that I published recently - Liquid video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-march/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manipulate JavaScript Arrays like a boss</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/manipulate-javascript-arrays-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/manipulate-javascript-arrays-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript arrays come with many useful methods. Mastering them can make you a much more efficient programmer. Let&#39;s have a look at a few of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git tip - How to stage a hunk of code via the command line</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/git-tip-staging-hunk-of-code-via-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/git-tip-staging-hunk-of-code-via-command-line/</guid>
      <description>GUI Git clients allow you to stage selected lines of code very easily. You may not know that but doing this in the command line isn&#39;t much more difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first year of blogging</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-first-year-of-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-first-year-of-blogging/</guid>
      <description>Exactly one year ago I published my first article. I&#39;m not going to stop here that&#39;s for sure. Nothing went wrong, so let me share with you what went well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 February</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-february/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Custom Properties explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-custom-properties-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-custom-properties-explained/</guid>
      <description>CSS Custom Properties (colloquially known as a CSS Variables) are around the corner. Let&#39;s embrace the power of a feature that we&#39;ve been waiting years for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s new in ECMAScript 2016 (ES7)</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2016-es7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/whats-new-in-ecmascript-2016-es7/</guid>
      <description>ES2015 brought a lot of large-scale features to the language. The new release process is going to introduce a few small bits every year. Here&#39;s what&#39;s new in ES2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2016 January</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2016-january/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image tag vs background property</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/image-tag-vs-background-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/image-tag-vs-background-property/</guid>
      <description>Images need to be treated differently dependent on whether they are part of the design or part of the content. Let&#39;s discuss backgrounds and images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rounding and truncating numbers in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/rounding-and-truncating-numbers-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/rounding-and-truncating-numbers-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Convert primary school math skills into code. Let&#39;s put together all that we know about rounding and truncating numbers in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite resources to learn JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-resources-to-learn-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-resources-to-learn-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Matt Mullenweg gave us a homework “Learn JavaScript, Deeply”. I wouldn’t want to disappoint the creator of WordPress so these are resources that I found helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 December</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-december/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background video made easy</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/background-video-made-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/background-video-made-easy/</guid>
      <description>HTML5 comes with video tag that we can use to create video as a background with a little bit help from CSS. Let’s add some movement to our projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 November</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-november/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favourite front-end related podcasts</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-front-end-related-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-favourite-front-end-related-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>We all know how difficult it is staying up to date in front-end development. The day is not long enough. The solution? Podcasts to the rescue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 October</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-october/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BEM with Emmet</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/bem-with-emmet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/bem-with-emmet/</guid>
      <description>Emmet is one of my favourite plugins for a lightning fast HTML &amp; CSS workflow. BEM methodology helps me to keep my projects sane. Let’s try them together!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets get into the basics of CSS Grid Layout Model</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/lets-get-into-the-basics-of-css-grid-layout-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/lets-get-into-the-basics-of-css-grid-layout-model/</guid>
      <description>The majority of websites are built based on some sort of grid and we use many techniques to achieve that. CSS Grid Layout Model is just around the corner!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 September</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-september/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret of “CSS Secrets” by Lea Verou</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-secret-of-css-secrets-by-lea-verou/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/the-secret-of-css-secrets-by-lea-verou/</guid>
      <description>Fall in love in stylesheets all over again with “CSS Secrets” by Lea Verou. Quick review of Lea’s amazing collection of CSS tricks, tips and advices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native feature detection with CSS.supports() API</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-feature-detection-with-csssupports-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/native-feature-detection-with-csssupports-api/</guid>
      <description>Feature detection is something that every front end developer faced at some point. CSS.supports() API allows us to use very elegant form to doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use modern JavaScript today with Babel</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/use-modern-javascript-today-with-babel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/use-modern-javascript-today-with-babel/</guid>
      <description>ECMAScript 2015 has been recently ratified and brought us many cool features. As you may expect, browsers support is the only issue, but not with Babel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarking with Pinboard</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/bookmarking-with-pinboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/bookmarking-with-pinboard/</guid>
      <description>The internet is full of things that you don&#39;t want to forget. Bookmarking services like Pocket or Delicious are helpful but Pinboard is much more than that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 August</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-august/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Sass to PostCSS</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-sass-to-postcss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/from-sass-to-postcss/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember that amazing feeling when you discovered the power of Sass? Variables, mixins, nesting — WOW! Time to do it again, this time with PostCSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I won&#39;t miss you Adobe</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-wont-miss-you-adobe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/i-wont-miss-you-adobe/</guid>
      <description>For years Adobe products were the obvious choice for web designers. Not because of it&#39;s incredibly good but there was no choice. Finally things changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix privileges and never again use sudo with npm</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/fix-priviliges-and-never-again-use-sudo-with-npm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/fix-priviliges-and-never-again-use-sudo-with-npm/</guid>
      <description>Running npm with sudo allows hackers to have full control over your computer. Fortunately it works perfectly fine without root powers. Let&#39;s fix it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 July</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-july/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Specificity explained</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-specificity-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/css-specificity-explained/</guid>
      <description>CSS Specificity is the most misunderstood part of Cascading Style Sheets. Let me explain how the browser understands and interprets the jungle of selectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 June</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-june/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript console in Sublime Text</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/javascript-console-in-sublime-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/javascript-console-in-sublime-text/</guid>
      <description>Reading books, attending conferences and watching videos is pointless without practice. Let me show you what helped me a lot on my JavaScript learning curve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 May</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-may/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you really need another grid system?</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/do-you-really-need-another-grid-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/do-you-really-need-another-grid-system/</guid>
      <description>CSS grid system is so easy to create. We can use one of thousands frameworks, but do we really have to? Let me show you how I do it with few SASS mixing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 April</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-april/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Sublime Text Snippets organized</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/keep-sublime-text-snippets-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/keep-sublime-text-snippets-organized/</guid>
      <description>Web development nowadays is a complex thing. Gazillion languages, techniques and functions are not easy to remmember. Let me remind you how cool snippets are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to stay informed in web development game</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/how-to-stay-informed-in-web-development-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/how-to-stay-informed-in-web-development-game/</guid>
      <description>Web design industry is very changeable. You need to flow new trends, frameworks, methodologies, concepts and standards to stay in the game. That’s how I do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll blog on Github Pages supercharged by CloudFlare</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/jekyll-blog-on-github-pages-supercharged-by-cloudflare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/jekyll-blog-on-github-pages-supercharged-by-cloudflare/</guid>
      <description>Building first Jekyll website can be tricky, but it’s worth to give it a try. Let me share why I chose Jekyll, what did I struggle with and why I love it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top picks — 2015 March</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/top-picks-2015-march/</guid>
      <description>Staying up to date in web industry is a difficult and time consuming task. I would like to share with you my top finds from the past month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My web development setup</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-web-development-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/my-web-development-setup/</guid>
      <description>I like to read about tools, software, frameworks and frequently used tricks and tips of web developers. Today I would like to show you my set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello there!</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/hello-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/hello-there/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my website. After a while of being a web developer I found out that It gives my a massive pleasure to share knowledge, so I decided to run this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uses</title>
      <link>https://pawelgrzybek.com/uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelgrzybek.com/uses/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
